right uh well let's kick start the show
with a focus on a cnbc tv 18 exclusive
sources have told us that insurer axa
may sell its entire stake in icici
lombard general insurance now my
colleague yash has been picking up all
of that he joins in with more details
yash over to you
that's correct sonia french insurer axa
insurance is looking to sell its entire
stake when it comes to the general
insurance company icici lombard general
insurance what we've been given to
understand from our sources is that axa
has floated a mandate
and that is essentially to sell its uh
around 3.8 percent stake which it holds
in icici lombard general insurance do
remember that this stake came to the
company as a part of the share shop
agreement which took place after icici
lombard decided to acquire and merge
bharti axa general insurance into itself
that's when under the share swap ratio
3.8 percent approximately stake is what
came to axa as as the shareholder of
bharti aksa general insurance and that
is expected to be sold by the company
what we are also told by our sources
that this transaction could be done in
one or more transfers depending on the
appetite of the hepatitis stronger axa
could look at uh selling this entire
stake in one go otherwise it could take
one or more tranches and it will be done
in uh the open market through a block
deal now just in terms of one number uh
access take as per the current cmp would
be around 2700 crore and that would
become essentially the block overhang
which will lie on icici lombard we've
written to both companies icici lombard
has said that they have no comment to
offer and we are awaiting a reply from
axa insurance
okay all right yeah sure thanks very
much for that so that's uh cnbc tv
exclusive but let's focus on the markets
then devina mehra the chairperson and md
of first global now joins in to discuss
all of the euphoria that we've seen
devina hi welcome to the show you know i
was reading one of your interviews
around a month ago where you said that
the small cap rally is actually nowhere
close to the danger mark zone and since
then we've only gained i mean we had
milestones for the sensex and the nifty
would you probably advocate a little bit
of caution at these levels now
yeah hi i mean good to be in the reverse
of a manual
men only panel that
one sees more usually so it's good to be
in an all-woman show
uh coming to your uh question see the
overall uh you know we talk about this
lake of returns theory that the
lake overflows
or rather danger of a bear market comes
when the returns have been far higher
than trend not just small cap i was
looking at the sensex because it went
past its 40 year mark some time ago and
i was looking at some data which was for
each decade so 1980 to 1990 to 2000 2000
to 2010 2010 to 2020 and the numbers
were like of i think 21 in the first
decade and 17 and 14
in the next two decades and 2010 to 20
was some eight and odd percent
so that decade actually was far far
below trend
so this whole movement that you saw from
the last year's covet lows
it's still not taken you even to the
trend line
which is why
you know my opinion has been that there
is not any great danger of a big bear
market
and which is true not
just of the broad market if you look at
the small caps again pretty much the
same story but i always always say that
small caps even when you say bullish it
is always cautiously bullish because it
is a risky end of the market and it's a
risky end of the market not just in
india but practically anywhere in the
world i was looking at the u.s data it's
pretty much the same there was some data
showing that small cap mutual funds in
the us outperformed over the long term
but once you uh adjusted for the funds
which had gone out of business or that
merged with other funds essentially you
know adjusted for the survivorship bias
you find that they have not really
outperformed so we are always
risk-averse we are cautious so even when
we like the small cap space we don't go
all out to buy it because we have many
strict parameters on liquidity etcetera
so if i look at our uh
pms schemes we have less than 10 percent
or around 10 percent in small caps small
cap definers below 5000 crores market
cap so we remain cautious there but as i
said on the market as a whole
given
the history of returns we are not really
in danger territory if you look at
rolling returns because still a
beginning of 2020 there was a very long
period when you had not even met fixed
deposit return then for five years in
fact you're not even making savings
deposit rates
so there was there was that room which
had been created for the market to go up
okay uh
morning you know you were saying that
you're glad to be a part of the all
woman team in front of the camera we
have a woman director as well rolling
the show so we have a woman sitting
behind the camera too and our producer
is also a woman so it's clearly women
power uh you know this this morning so
why not why not of course um no gender
bias is here but anyway you know so you
said that there's no real risk of a bear
market or you know there's no real risk
of a big detailing of this market right
now what does one do then do you
continue to invest in if yes which are
the pockets where there is still growth
potential and valuations are still not
you know sky high
so let me just you know temper that by
saying that when i say no big risk of a
big bear market doesn't mean that there
cannot be significant corrections
because in any move there can be
significant corrections and if you look
at india it is not as if that we have no
macro concerns you still have a lot of
uh uh
things not quite okay on the economy
front
with citizens and therefore consumers
suffering
and there is of course because of the
commodity prices going up there's been
pressure on margins also in certain
segments you just spoke of consumer
durables you know even fmcg to some
extent it's facing similar thing with an
inability to necessarily pass on the
price height so it's not that it's like
a risk-free zone and uh you know i can
tell you the way we manage funds as i
said our
whole approach is to be cautious which
means that we are fairly diversified we
don't take outsized sector bets so
that's part of the story
uh and actually if i look at the top
weights it's not changed a whole lot i
mean we
still have uh chemicals uh fairly high
up i.t is probably the highest even you
know it's not outside but it is the
highest and not just i.t services but
certain other segments of technology uh
because this was a
trade that we identified last year
you know when fmcgs were the flavor of
the season and i said that this is
another industry where you have
fairly stable
prospects decent margins returns but the
valuations were a fraction of what fmcg
is used to trade at so there has been
some re-rating plus it's uh you know
dollar heads it's more predictable so
all those things so that that was a nice
space to be in we
did play the commodity play from third
quarter onwards last year but we cut
back quite significantly after having
made uh
quite substantial money in that
especially steel because
non-ferrous there is still
room steel i think it will be like not
not bad but no longer great
so
that's been the broad outlook
davina a little short on time today but
i really want to ask you this what do
you say is uh the color of the money
that's coming in i mean a lot of the
investors that are with first global for
instance i mean is it a different
profile more younger people if at all
and what would you say to a whole
generation of first-time investors
who've not really seen a brutal bear
market yet
yeah be cautious as i as i tweeted
recently you know don't confuse a bull
market with brains so so don't attribute
all your success to how
smart you are
because the bull market will
make you look better than you are
and yes i mean it's good that younger
people are getting interesting we'll be
interested we get a lot of uh messages
asking for products for smaller
investors so we are just about to in a
matter of two to three weeks we'll be
launching on the small case platform so
that is something that you know the
younger and newer investors can look
forward to
and uh as you know all those statistics
on compounding show that the sooner you
start the better off you are at the end
of your
uh when you retire or whenever you hang
up your boots which is which is a good
thing so even if you start five or ten
years later you need a far higher rate
of compounding to get to your retirement
corpus
okay davina it's been a pleasure but um
i completely take your point you cannot
mistake a bull market with brains thanks
very much for joining in and talking to
us so we'll take a short break now but
we'll get chatting with shashvat goenka
who's the sector head of retail and fmcg
at the sanjeev goenka group on their
foray into the personal care segment on
the other side stay tuned